SIRUI ZHU

Portfolio available at : siruizhu.github.io

SELECTED PROJECTS

Tianwen1 to mars

Using JavaScript for interactive and responsive web design.

What can we tell from the evolution of Han Chinese names? (Freelance work for Kontinentalist)

Using JavaScript and D3.js developing two interactive graphics showing the evolution of male/female top 20 given names and developing the searching name function.

China's Long March to space

Researching China's space program and processing data. Using After effects for animations, Illustrator for rockets illustrations, using Ai2html and responsive web design.

<u>A look at Alibaba's "Double 11" shopping day, the world's largest online retail event</u>

Researching on Chinese Singles' Day shopping event. Gathering and processing data. Using illustrations and animation to highlight the visuals, using JavaScript to develop interactive charts.

Vaping crisis

Researching on vaping issues in the U.S., came up with ideas and illustrations, using JavaScript to develop interactive charts.

EDUCATION

Lede Program for Data Journalism, Columbia University

May 2018 - Dec. 2018 New York, USA

Courses: Python, data analysis with pandas, matplotlib, SQL, JavaScript, D3.js, basic machine learning (regression and prediction) and text analysis, web app development, geographic analysis with QGIS, Scrollytelling.

M.A., Broadcast Journalism, University of Sheffield

Sept. 2014 - Sept. 2015 Sheffield, UK

Portfolio: London's Chinatown Feels the Squeeze of Rent Rises (video)

B.A., Broadcasting and Compering, Wuhan University

Sept. 2010 - June 2014 Wuhan, China

Dissertation: Analysis of China Reality Show from the Perspective of Communication.

AWARDS & VOLUNTEER

Excellent Journalist of Wuhan University 2011.6
Excellent Student for University Article Writing Competition for
Xinhai Revolution 100th Anniversary 2011.10
Sheffield Student Union Charity Hitchhike 2015.3
Wuhan Green NGO Oct. 2011

Rm2004, Building 5, Taihua Binheyuan, Chaoyang District,

Beijing, China. 100026 **Tel:** (+86) 18607165112

Email: surizhu9@gmail.com | zhusirui9@163.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data: Python, pandas, matplotlib, SQL, APIs,

Selenium, BeautifulSoup

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js, Ai2html

Mapping: QGIS, Mapbox, Leaflet Services: Github, Git, Travis, Heroku Applications: Adobe Illustrator,

Photoshop, After Effects, Adobe Premiere, Final

Cut Pro, Edius

Language: Mandarin(Native) English(Professional)

WORK EXPERIENCE

<u>Data viz editor</u> | Beijing, China

August 2020 to present

Doing story research, writing and developing interactive graphics and pages.

Freelance dataviz developer | China

April 2020 to present

Designing graphics and pitching ideas to organizations.

<u>Thomson Reuters</u> | New York, USA

Data visualization developer intern April 1st 2019 to Dec. 31 2019

Designing and developing interactive & static graphics for daily news and special reports; Reporting data-driven stories, topics include immigration, finance, culture and environment.

Wuhan Dyclub Data Technology Lit.Co. Wuhan, China

Training Supervisor Nov. 2016 - May 2018

Organized more than twenty Dyclub data journalism online training. Managed and wrote articles on Wechat channel's special column "Weekly Data Journalism."

Hubei Televisions | Wuhan, China

TV Producer Mar 2016 - Oct. 2016

Produced children's reality shows and wrote children's show scripts.

UK Chinese Times | London, UK

News Editor intern June 2015 - July 2015 Edited international news pieces

China National Radio | Beijing

News Editor intern Feb. 2013 - May 2013

Edited radio news, worked on 2013 NPC and CPPCC reporting for two weeks.